dots.com 2012-11-09

# Privacy and Security: Dots.com

Welcome to the Dots, LLC's ("Dots") website. Because your privacy is very important to us, we want you to understand our practices with regard to collecting and using personal information obtained online and the steps we take to safeguard it. This statement applies to "personally identifiable information" collected online from our customers, which means information that identifies a particular individual, such as the individual's name, postal address, e-mail address, credit card number, and telephone number. When other information, such as, for example, consumer product preferences, or number of children, is directly associated with personally identifiable information, this other information also becomes personally identifiable information for purposes of this Privacy Policy. Personally identifiable information is sometimes referred to in this Privacy Policy as "personal information."

 ** _I. Information We Collect_

a. Personally Identifiable Information

**  
We may collect Personally Identifiable Information (including name, address, telephone number, e-mail address and, when necessary, credit card information) when you:  

* Place an order from our stores or on our Web site

* Return an item or make an exchange online

* Inquire online about our services

* Receive a gift package

* Create an account at Dots.com

* Subscribe to our E-mail Newsletter

* Enter an online contest or sweepstakes

* Participate in a marketing survey, promotion or event online.

**b. Aggregate Information**  
Our website collects some non-personal information about you using clickstream technology, so it may not be readily apparent to you that it is being collected. For instance, when you come to our site your IP address is collected.

An IP address is often associated with the place from which you enter the Internet like your ISP (Internet service provider), your company, or your university. This information is not personally identifiable and we do not combine this type of information with personally identifiable information.

**c. Cookies**  
Dots, directly or through an outside service, may place "cookies" on your computer so we can collect information related to your use of dots.com. This information allows us to refine and improve the site for our customers. Cookies do NOT collect any credit card, user name or password information or any other personally identifiable information.

 ** _II. Use of Personal Information We Collect_

a. Personally Identifiable Information

**  
At Dots, we always want to provide you with the best possible shopping experience and fulfill your orders exactly as you've requested. In order to do this, we use your personally identifiable information to allow us to:  

* Process and track your order

* Provide the services you request

* Contact you about the status of an order

* Send you catalogs or promotional offers we believe will be of interest to you

* Send you the Dots E-mail Newsletter, if you do not ask to be excluded

* Identify your product and service preferences

* Customize our communications to you

* Provide information concerning product recalls or products you have purchased

* Improve our merchandise selection and customer service

* Administer a sweepstakes or similar promotion and identify or publicize the winner(s) in accordance with the rules for that promotion.

Your e-mail address will not be shared with any third parties, except as described below. Instructions for unsubscribing are included in every e-mail.

**b. Aggregate Information**  
We use the aggregate information that we collect from our customers in a manner that does not personally identify any individual. We use aggregate information to make our sites more interesting and useful to you. We also track the pages or documents accessed within our site. This information is collected for systems administration and for analyzing and improving the value of the material available on our website. This aggregate non-personal information is used to help our advertisers or our site design team to create advertisements our guests might like.

 ** _III. Information We Share with Others_

a. Our Contractors

**  
We contract with other companies (credit card processors, shippers, sweepstakes promoters, website developers and others) to provide certain services to Dots to fulfill orders, provide sweepstakes, and create or maintain our website. In some instances, these contractors may have access to personally identifiable information, but they are contractually obligated to maintain the confidentiality of the information and to use it only for purposes of carrying out Dots business.

In some instances, you may choose to deal with some of these contractors directly and provide your personal information to them. For example, when you make a purchase from Dots with a credit card, you may choose to use an independent card processor, such as PayPal. In those instances, you should check the privacy policies on their independent websites that will govern the collection and use of personal information that you give to them directly.

**b. Disclosure Exceptions**

Notwithstanding the above policies, we reserve the right to disclose your personal information to third parties as appropriate or if we are required to do so by law or we believe that such action is necessary:

  * To comply with legal process such as a search warrant, subpoena or court order;

  * To protect the company's rights and property;

  * To investigate reports of fraud or of users sending material using a false e-mail address or users sending harassing, threatening, or abusive messages;

  * To protect against misuse or unauthorized use of our web site; or

  * During emergencies, such as when we believe someone's physical safety is at risk

 ** _IV. E-mail Use_**

When you provide us your e-mail address, we may send you e-mails necessary to process your order or respond to a request, or to receive our E-mail Newsletter. For example, after you place an order at Dots.com, you will receive an e-mail confirmation and, in most cases, an e-mail with package tracking information. Recipients of our Electronic Gift Certificates will receive an e-mail notifying them of the gift and instructing them how to redeem it. 

It is our intent to send you promotional e-mail (our E-mail Newsletter). Instructions on how to unsubscribe are included in each edition of the newsletter.

 ** _V. Links to Other Sites_**

Occasionally we provide links on our web site to other sites we think you will enjoy. These sites operate independently of Dots and have established their own privacy and security policies. Dots does not have any control over these sites' privacy practices. For the best online experience, we strongly encourage you to review these policies at any site you visit.

 ** _VI. Security_**

It is our intent to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information that we have collected from you. We use a variety of current technologies and processes for protection of our customer data. We limit the information we provide to outside companies with whom we contract only what they need to carry out their responsibilities.

When you make a purchase, request a catalog or create an account on our web site, your transactional information is transmitted in a safe, encrypted format. We maintain the data you provide, along with a record of your purchases, in a secure database.

 ** _VII. Privacy of Children to Our Web Site_**

Our web site is not intended for use by children under the age of 13, and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13.

 ** _VIII. Policy Changes_**

From time to time, we may use customer information for unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our privacy notice. If our information practices change, we will post these changes on our web site. We encourage you to review our privacy policy periodically.

This policy was last updated on November 5, 2012.

 ** _IX. Comments or Questions?_**

We welcome any and all comments, questions and feedback. For privacy-related issues, or to make a subscription change, cancel catalogs or E-mail newsletters, or otherwise, please contact us at:

Dots, LLC  
30300 Emerald Valley Parkway  
Glenwillow, OH 44139  
1-800-208-8173

Or by e-mailing us through our [Contact Us](http://www.dots.com/custserv/contactus.jsp) page.

 ** _X. Additional Topics of Interest_**

In addition to our Privacy Policy, read our [Terms of Use](http://www.dots.com/custserv/custserv.jsp?pageName=Terms).
